Steps for labeling a map.
For labeling a map, you should take
the following
steps.
Firstly, look at the map to identify fixed
locations.
Next, we need to identify the direction and
describe the position of locations we need to
label on the map.
If the question's requirement is to fill in
words on a map, then you should pay
attention to the word limit.
In step 3, you have to listen and
fill in the correct answers in each blank.
In case you get lost, take notes immediately
and do not panic.
Finally, you have to check your answers after listening.
You will not lose points if you write
the incorrect answers, so never leave your answer
sheet blank.
Let's look at an example together.
In this example, the question requires you to
find the position of five locations on the
map and write the correct letter.
A to I.
Here are the steps for this type of
exercise.
Step 1.
Identify fixed locations.
Here, we can immediately see that the main
building is near the middle of the map
with an emergency exit on the right side.
When we get out of the main building,
we will be on the main road.
When we get out of the main building
and turn right, we will reach Anita Road.
Near the locations A, E and F, there
are some trees and there is a back
gate on the right border of the map.
Step 2.
Identify the direction.
In step 2, we have to identify the
direction and describe the position of locations from
A to I on the map.
In this exercise, the starting point may be
the main building.
To describe location G, you may hear the
following instruction in the recording.
You get out of the main building, turn
right and G is on the left side.
To reach location C, you may hear the following
sentence.
You go out of the emergency exit, C
is on your right.
In the listening test, you will not have
a lot of time for this step before
the recording starts, so it's important that you
practice making these predictions fast.
In step 3, you have to listen to the
recording and fill in the correct answers.
When you get lost, remember to take notes
immediately.
And step 4, after listening, you have to check
your answers and never leave your answer
sheet blank.
Next, you will listen to the recording and
complete this map in the practice section.
See you soon!